Become more efficient with background
posting.
In Business Central, you can let the
system post journals and documents in
the background, so you can continue
working on other tasks and not have to
wait for posting to complete.
This is especially useful when posting
journals and documents with significant
amount of lines.
You can set this up in pages such as
general ledger setup, sales and
receivable setup, and purchase and
payable setup.
Let's go to purchase and payable setup
to learn how to enable background
posting.
I bring up the tell me search with Alt
Q.
I search for purchase and payables, and
select purchase and payable setup from
the list.
I browse down to find the background
posting section.
I enable post with job queue.
And in this case, I also enable post and
print with job queue, because I want to
get notified on my role center when my
purchase documents have been posted and
printed.
We'll see how that works.
Let's now go and post and print a
purchase order.
Go to purchasing in the top navigation
menu, select purchase orders,
and I select the purchase order that I
want to post and print.
I then select post and post and print.
I want to receive an invoice this
purchase order, and select okay.
Now it says that the purchase order has
been scheduled for posting in the
background.
That's great.
Let's go back to the role center.
I'm back at the role center,
and I expect to find the posted purchase
order sitting in my report inbox.
I browse down to find the report inbox,
and as I expect, I find two posted
documents here.
One is the printed purchase receipt from
the purchase order, and another is the
posted purchase invoice.
I can open these documents in OneDrive
by selecting the ellipsis menu, and
select open in OneDrive.
This will open the document in OneDrive
if you have cloud files enabled for your
Business Central. So, with this, we
learned how we can
post documents in the background
and see when they're posted when they
turn up in our reporting box and open
these files with OneDrive.
Thank you for watching.